Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 37.
This exercise, we are asked throughout the program to rotate an array clockwise.
We have sold like this example in the lecture and the previous videos.
But we need to implement it in real life, so we need to make a program that rotate and array clockwise,
so we need to switch the last element to become the first element.
This is the trick behind this question.
Host the video and think about it.
Try to implement your own code.
Now we need to start by
making method here.
I will call it as public static void.
It's returning type and called Rotate the Adderly.
OK.
In a equal to equal to array.
This is.
It took an end of a year.
My I my gray keeps my enemy
OK.
So my array.
And Lang and Ray Meyer rate at length minus one, we need to switch to elements.
OK.
It's very simple.
No, I will create and and I also
for I can create it here
for int I equal to arrays my array dog length
minus one and I greater than zero and a plus plus or minus minus because we are switching from the last
to the beginning.
OK, so my array at index, I equaled my array at index minus one.
We start by moving the elements, switching the elements from the last to the beginning.
OK.
And here are my array at index zero equal to Hey.
It's very simple.
Now in the main, the main method I will create is an end array
called my array or array.
One ought not be confused, not a new entry.
And I passed the following elements.
OK, now I need to make
my axis, then that out.
Dot, print
and.
Or original outlay?
Is it is the same as.
At least not to drink.
I'm using a to string a one.
OK.
This is very simple.
Now we called the method rotate array and we pass at a one and then the same, the same thing I need
to display there a rotated that they rotate the array arrays to string array one.
OK.
So this will display the original array and this will be rotating the array.
And this would be displaying the rtated array.
OK, let's run and see, we have the original array here.
And the rotated array, we have just moved the last element and put it inside or replacing the first
element, and these would be shifting to the right by one place.
OK, let's try to rotate the element by two times.
Let's run, Nancy.
And here we go.
We called the method one time, so it was removed.
It will be rotated by one time.
This element would be replacing here, but we have called the method two times.
So this element, these two elements have been replacing the first and the second.
And these elements would be shifting to cells.
So 10 would not be replacing.
20, it would be replacing 30.
OK.
Because then now at the third album, this is how this.